<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infosec on Quac Tran</title>
    <link>https://tranquac.github.io/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infosec on Quac Tran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tranquac.github.io/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OSCP CheatSheet Full</title>
      <link>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/04/oscp-cheatsheet-full/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/04/oscp-cheatsheet-full/</guid>
      <description>This is all I have gathered from my practice and oscp exam. It is quite complete. Hope it will help your exam.
 Try Harder
 Finding Around Kali Find, Locate, and Which locate Reads from a database prepared by updatedb
updatedb
locate ssh.config
which Returns pathnames of files or links which would be executed in the current environment. It does this by searching the PATH variable.
which python
find  find / -name &#39;file*&#39; find / -name &#39;foldername&#39; -type d find / -name &#39;filename&#39; -type f find / -name &#39;sbd*&#39; -exec file {} \;  Managing Kali Linux Services The standard Kali services include ssh, http, sql, which by default would load at boot time, however Kali prevents this by not allowing that, and includes a management system to control their status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the OSCP Certification: &#39;Offensive Security Certified Professional&#39; (PEN-200) review</title>
      <link>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/04/getting-the-oscp-certification-offensive-security-certified-professional-pen-200-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/04/getting-the-oscp-certification-offensive-security-certified-professional-pen-200-review/</guid>
      <description>28-4-2021 / 21 Year Old  Hôm nay tôi ngồi đây để viết những dòng suy nghĩ này khi tôi vừa nhận được email thông báo tôi đã vượt qua kì thi OSCP của offensive security.Đây chỉ là một bài viết đơn giản để tôi có thể chia sẻ những suy nghĩ,cảm nhận và hành trình tôi đạt đượt chứng chỉ OSCP trong lần thi đầu tiền . Đó là cả một quá trình gian nan, cố gắng hết mình của tôi trong 3 tháng.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux privilege escalation full</title>
      <link>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/03/linux-privilege-escalation-full/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tranquac.github.io/posts/2021/03/linux-privilege-escalation-full/</guid>
      <description>Linux-Privilege-Escalation Synthesize, supplement from a number of other resources Editing and addition: TranQuac Summary  Tools Scheduled tasks  Cron jobs Systemd timers   PATH Variables SUID  Find SUID binaries Exploitation Create a SUID binary   Capabilities  List capabilities of binaries Edit capabilities Interesting capabilities   SUDO  Allow Root Privilege to Binary commands Allow Root Privilege to Shell Script Allow Sudo Right to other Programs LD_PRELOAD Doas sudo_inject CVE-2019-14287   GTFOBins Wildcard Writable files  Writable /etc/passwd Writable /etc/sudoers   Exploiting Services  Services manual enumeration Automatic enumeration Port forwarding   NFS Root Squashing Shared Library  ldconfig RPATH   Groups  Docker LXC/LXD   Kernel Exploits  CVE-2016-5195 (DirtyCow) CVE-2010-3904 (RDS) CVE-2010-4258 (Full Nelson) CVE-2012-0056 (Mempodipper) LIST KERNEL    Tools There are many scripts that you can execute on a linux machine which automatically enumerate sytem information, processes, and files to locate privilege escelation vectors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
